http://www.daughtersofcharity.org.uk/privacy.aspx

Life Stories
Are you being called?
Is this for me?
Privacy Policy Overview
Daughters of Charity of St Vincent de Paul is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its website users and customers. We have written this privacy policy to outline the specific information we collect, how we use this information, and what options you have in sharing this information with us when you visit our site. Protecting your privacy is a significant part of our commitment to providing you with a high quality website.
Information Collection and Use
We are the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will never sell, share, or rent this information to others... ever. Daughters of Charity of St Vincent de Paul collects information from our users at several different points on our website. We will use this information to contact you, and keep you informed of our services.
Links
This web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that Daughters of Charity of St Vincent de Paul is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Daughters of Charity of St Vincent de Paul.
Newsletter/Bulletin
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter and/or update bulletin, should this be available, we ask for the user's email address. You will be sent an e-mail to confirm your request, then added to our mailing list. An unsubscribe link is provided on our newsletter/bulletin page to remove your e-mail address from our list.
Notification of Changes
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected
Cookie Policy
A new legislation on internet cookies stipulates that web users must be provided with the opportunity to learn how cookies are used on the web sites they visit, and must consent to cookies being utilised. You can be assured that the our Website does not use cookies to track your activity online.
What is a Cookie?
In terms of the internet, a cookie is a small text file which is placed on your computer when you access a web site. The cookie will usually contain information such as; the web site’s name, a user ID, the extent of the cookie’s effect, and a unique number. Cookies will not reveal your identity, or indeed any personal information.
In most cases, on the first occasion that you go to a web site that uses cookies, a cookie will be placed on your computer. Next time you go to that web site, your device (computer/laptop/mobile/tablet/etc.) will search for a cookie that corresponds to this web site, and will send the information held in the cookie back to the site. From there, the web site can identify that you have visited previously. This allows some web sites to alter the information presented to you based on this fact. Using cookies, some web sites may also record how much time you spend viewing certain pages of the site, the pages/links you have selected, and save preferences you have chosen during your visit.
For the most part, cookies bring many benefits to the internet user, especially if you visit some web sites on a regular basis - your preferences are saved so that you don’t have to re-enter or re-select details or options. Additionally, cookies help to improve internet shopping, i.e they are used to remember the items you have placed in your basket before checking out.
Daughters of Charity of St Vincent de Paul use only two types of Cookies:
Session Cookies
Session Cookies are essential for the operation of our website and they expire after each browser session. These session cookies are therefore only temporary.
Persistent Cookies
Persistent Cookies are also used on www.daughtersofcharity.org.uk/ but they do not collect any information which identifies a user.  However these persistent cookies do collect information on how each visitor to the site uses it and records which pages are visited for analytical purposes.  The user cannot be identified only their flow through the website and the pages visited.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This, however, may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Your Feedback
At Daughters of Charity of St Vincent de Paul, your privacy is extremely important. You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, or have any questions about the privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with us, please Contact Us and let us know. Thank you.
Home
About Us
Spirit
Mission
Ministry
Community
News
VOCATIONS
Are you being called?
Is this for me?
Copyright (c) 2020 Daughters of Charity.
All Rights Reserved
Website Designed & Maintained by PMG Web. Website Design Glasgow
Login
